here.
>> Me here.
>> Gary, did anyone hear from Gary?
>> Is he on another overseas thing?
>> Oh, I'm not sure. I don't know if he
said
>> Okay. Okay. Uh, David
>> here.
>> Don. Anyone hear from Don?
Not online. Josh
>> here.
>> Elizabeth
>> Patrick Butos
>> here.
>> Kelly
>> Patrick Bon.
Anyone hear from him?
>> Yeah, Madam Chair. I'd uh just talked to
Patrick and he is uh unable to be here
at the meeting, but he uh wanted to cuz
respects everybody and let you all know
that he uh he does intend to try to get
back uh to a pos to a situation where he
can join meetings again. Um he was going
to try to get online, but he just didn't
feel well enough to do it tonight.
>> He wanted to give his regards to
everybody.
>> And John
>> here.
Okay, think we have enough for a quorum.
>> Chuck.
>> Oh,
>> Chuck, I'm sorry. I was just reading
right on on here.
>> Noted. I I will know that for our
conference this coming weekend or week.
Um, okay. So, uh, the minutes, approval
of the minutes. Does anyone want to make
a motion?
>> I will. So, move
to approve the minutes as submitted.
Second.
>> Second. Is there any discussion?
No.
Okay. Um,
sorry, my brain is only half working
right now, guys. Uh, can we vote to uh
approve the meeting minutes?
>> Say all in favor?
>> All in favor? Thank you. All in favor? I
>> I
>> um is there any disclosures or conflicts
that anyone needs to
say up front? No. Um audience business.
Do we have anyone online?
Okay. Comments reports from city council
which Hillward just shared that Ken
Esville will be out this evening.
Um
so comments and report from planning and
development.
Um chair 3, we do not have any updates.
Um
the
planning and development office is
having um their annual review with the
UDC, but um that's about the only thing
that is going on right now.
Hey, strategic goals report. Uh,
National Register's Historic Places.
Elizabeth, do you want to
>> Yeah. Um, I don't have anything too
exciting for us this month. It's kind of
just continuing what I've already been
and working on of piling resources,
um, going through those, finding
additional sources out of those. Um, so
really right now it's kind of the messy
part of putting it all together in a um
a way that I can get something out of
it, if you will. Um so kind of the same
for both of them. Um the National
Register nomination and the context
study are pretty much in the same place
right now of just digging through stuff
right now. Um I did have a question
though. I still haven't received any
payment for those contracts. I don't
know if there's an update on that. chair
to um Charles is still working with our
finance department to get those paid. Um
they currently were well for the airport
terminal they were they invoiced
um the Cheyenne Arts I believe to get
that match. So that invoice has gone out
um and we're waiting for that to come
in. And then
for the other payment um they are just
working on with finance and so it should
hopefully be soon.
>> All right. Thank you. I also had a
question because we received a notice um
from Shipo on the CLG in a report. Was
that something that is supposed to come
from Elizabeth or from us? I was I think
Milward, were you on that email?
>> Yeah, that the final report was late.
>> Yeah, I I guess I'm not aware of what
report this is.
>> It would be a was a report on the CLG
grant.
>> Okay.
>> They received I think Josh, you were
asking who's usually compiles those and
>> Well, that's I I noticed there was a
random group of board members that was
on this email. It wasn't all of the
board members, but I forwarded it to
Charles and asked him and I didn't get
get a response. So, I didn't know if
anybody was working on it, but I think
it was um
more of like our annual report as a CLG,
not a not a specific grant. It's like
our annual report as a CLG to
>> um Katie at the Shipo. And so I don't
know maybe you have
>> um I think for the
I started compiling that um I think I
sent it to Millard at some point in
time.
>> A draft?
>> Yeah, just a draft. But I haven't and
Charles, but I hadn't heard anything
from either. Um,
I don't know if I should resend that to
somebody. Um,
>> pro probably because they were they were
looking for it. We're overdue on
whatever it is and I was like, I don't
know what this is.
>> And then Yeah. And then we haven't done
it for 2025 at all.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> So, we we need something together. Well,
and I emailed uh Katie back to ask her
for clarification and I did not hear
back from her. So, okay.
>> I was unsure.
And then
>> what was happening?
>> Do I just send that to everybody or
certain people on the board that want to
review it?
>> We don't know what it it is. So I
>> maybe just send it to everyone and then
>> um if it's something that we need to
look over at our strategic planning
meeting and we can figure out what needs
to go on the 2025 report.
>> Yeah. And I can also send along
>> the annual report.
>> The
>> it was due. It's the annual report uh to
this to the shipo from us as a CLG. It
was due on the 31st of January.
>> So I'll send along the last one that was
done by Lonnie um and then also what I
had compiled so far and I'll start the
2025 one with the information that I do
have um and send that along as well.
So for the because we have a CLG for the
nominations, right? Weren't we supposed
to have some sort of matching?
I guess I don't know what the terms were
for that. Is there a report that we need
to have specifically for the grants that
we do have?
>> No. So So what Katie was trying to get
from us is our annual report as a CLG.
what we've done as a CLG. I don't think
it has anything to do with the actual
grants we're getting from them.
>> Right. But do we need to do anything for
the the grants as far as like annual
reporting? Because I know we have like
whatever two to three years to complete
it, but we don't have to submit anything
in the interim.
>> I don't know. That would be a question
for staff. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. I can say I didn't see anything
along those lines in the contracts.
Okay. at least. Gotcha. Just want to
make sure we aren't missing anything
we're supposed to be reporting.
>> Yeah. And I don't know what the penalty
is for a late report. I don't know if
maybe you can just ask for an extension.
Um I imagine they would grant that, but
you sure don't want to get in a
situation where your status as a CLG is
imperiled because we didn't submit an
annual report. I know we've done it
every year. I think they've been
prepared by staff and then forwarded to
us for comment and approval and
assistance and I remember kind of coming
into the city office and signing off on
them.
>> Okay,
gotcha.
>> Yeah, I guess
>> and I'm quing my emails and I don't uh I
don't see anything from you. Maybe you
could resend it.
>> Okay.
I know that Microsoft Outlook had a
little bit of a blip the last couple
weeks, so could have also gotten lost in
transition. Trans. Yeah.
>> Well, I guess anything else on the
National Register?
Nothing.
Oral history projects.
>> Um just a quick update that I have my
next um oral history scheduled for next
week. Um, so that still sort of moving
forward on that. Um, kind of slowly, but
>> the next one is scheduled. So,
>> that's great.
>> Um, it's another uh longtime employee of
the green door. So, yep.
>> Little bit of a tangent, but I was
listening to a podcast on Anona Judge
who was um a slave to George Washington
and Marth Martha Washington. And the
only reason why we know the history of
what happened to her is because someone
took an oral history
of of of her experience and h and had
that in order to capture that history.
So I mean just to be able to do this for
Cheyenne I
think we're doing a really great thing.
So
um historic preservation month I think
um Don was kind of chairing that
if I recall. Um, so I think that's
probably something that we can discuss
at our strategic planning meeting of how
we want to move that forward because as
you mentioned in the last meeting,
Patrick, we really need to jump on
getting that out there for nominations
and
um
doing something. Yes, exactly. Be good
to give out their ward in the month of
May if we can.
Um, but I think that's something that we
could probably go over in strategic
planning.
Um, education of the public and
>> Oh, go ahead.
>> Chair along those lines. I um I don't
know. I it I don't have Dawn's
information, but it might be us to reach
out to Dawn and and and see if he's
going to continue. If not, then we
should consider, you know, passing that
on to somebody else at the uh strategic
meeting because um we just haven't heard
from him and I don't know what his
situation is, but hopefully by the the
strategic meeting we can have some
clarification on if he's going to
continue or not.
>> Yeah. You did you hear from him at all?
No word?
>> Haven't heard a thing. Um, I know that
he's got a really difficult life
circumstance. So, I think that's right.
There needs to be kind of a moment of
clarity here because you're you're kind
of losing the effectiveness of an open
position without somebody who's willing
to be active and able to be active.
>> Yeah.
So, yeah, I definitely think that's
that'll be a big one for the strategic
plan and for social media, too, because
that's another one that um we need to
kind of pick up on. So,
um, education of the public,
>> uh, went over to the library to, you
know, the Catholic school over here, uh,
they have their kids in the third grade
build models of historic buildings. and
I'm going to try to coordinate with them
so that we can get when the kids take
the stuff over to get uh either channel
5 or 27 or both to come over and then
also try to see if we can put some of
their things on our Facebook page
because some of the models are quite
cute. So,
>> when are they doing that?
They usually do it uh they at the li
they show up at the library in the
middle of November, but they work on the
buildings prior to that. They they show
them at St. Mary's and uh mostly the
parents come in and the kids give an
oral report and show off the buildings
and things. And then they uh have them
in their library for a month and then
they in like middle of November they
take them over to the Laram County
Library and then they're there for about
a month in the on the second floor on
the children's section there. So, but
there's they really haven't had too much
uh publicity of it but I thought we
could you know the the school the
library and we could get some
publicity out of it. So
>> yeah absolutely.
Um, ornaments. Um,
>> chair.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> I just had a comment and I I spoke with
Elizabeth about this just a moment ago
and I I should save it for the retreat,
but I'll forget.
Um,
I was a member of the Kansas City
Historic Preservation Board and I still
get their emails. And one of the things
they're doing for Black History Month is
they're putting out a list of all the
Black History uh places that are on the
National Register or have cultural
significance. And and Josh and
Elizabeth, I don't know where we'll be
next year, but maybe that's something we
could think about as part of education
of the public next year. gives us a year
to kind of be thinking that we might be
able we might be at a point where we
might be able to say something about
what we're doing and tie it into Black
History Month. It kind of gives us
hopefully a an an avenue and an
opportunity to to to, you know,
highlight some of the Black History
stuff that we may have discovered or
we're working on. It's it's it's a
thought. I know it's a year away, but um
it's something we should maybe think
about.
>> I think that's a fantastic idea and if
we can make it happen before the end of
the month, I mean, we know that the
Inner Ocean Hotel was owned um and I'm
forgetting his name right now. Liz,
>> yes, thank you. Um but that one I think
we could easily make a probably a quick
post even for this month about um
because we do have that information.
Um, no, that's a great idea.
>> Yeah, I was also going to say if we
wanted to get more involved on socials
with kind of the things that I'm I don't
want to say uncovering, but writing
about, if there's like a post a month of
like, hey, we found this photo. Here's a
quick write up about it. Um, that way we
kind of share that we're doing these
projects. Um, that's something I'd be
willing to do as well.
Yeah, I think that would be fantastic. I
guess any more comments on
um
ornaments?
Gary's not here, so I'm assuming we
don't have any report on ornaments.
Um airport fountain planning. Uh we did
meet um it was a week or two ago. Um and
I did see Kelly, I I saw an email. I did
not get to read it. I don't know if you
want to update on reaching out to
>> Yeah, sorry. It was a little bit last
minute today. [laughter]
>> It's okay.
>> Um Milward had shared um contact
information for the gal at the now I'm
going to forget Pacific Coast
>> Coast
>> conservation company that's out of
Colorado that Patrick had been talking
to. Um, and so I did speak to her
briefly today just to try to get a
little bit of an update since we've had
some personnel changes and um, wanted to
see where they were at. So it sounds
like Milward had shared with her the
most recent information and um, I don't
know if there was a
Yeah, I think it was the report from
Mountain Masonry that did the
restoration on the fountain. What was
that? Five years agoish.
um and came out and looked at it after
the hail stom,
>> right?
Um yeah, I could when I can sure flesh
out some of this. So, her name is
Lucinda Linderman and she's with Pacific
Coast Conservation and she and two or
three of her associates have been
involved with this. So, part Madam
Chair, part of the process was kind of
getting a handoff from Patrick Van in
terms of the things that he was in
charge with with the airport fountain.
One of them was um trying to kind of
look into and get some clarity on where
we were with getting the damage uh
fixed. And uh he had worked with
Mountain Masonry who had done the work
clear back in 2021 and then he had found
the Pacific Coast uh conservation
organization got a hold of them. they
came here in person. And when I kind of
uh took over his part of that and
started to communicate with her, she
said, I just basically asked her, "What
more do you need in order to give us a
proposal um for what it would what you
would charge us to do the repair work?"
And she said, "I need some uh missing
pieces of crucial information. One of
which is if a certain type of epoxy was
used uh by mountain masonry when they
did the original work, they need to know
exactly what that was." So when they if
they have to strip any of it off,
they're doing it correctly. So I got a
hold of Mike in Mountain Masonry and he
was very nice and forthcoming and he
said, "I'm happy to provide everything
that we've got." Um Lucinda was also
looking for some before pictures
uh to to get an idea of of what the
final um restoration should look like,
what it looked like before, so they can
kind try to match that as much as
possible. And fortunately, um, Mountain
Mason Street has a ton of photos, so I
put together a Google Drive and, um,
gave them access to it so they could
just upload everything into a drive. Um,
so all of his reports, including the hay
damage one, every official, I mean, he
put everything in there, every official
document. I mean, it's going to have, I
think, way more than they probably need,
but um, they'll be familiar with how to
sift through it. He also said that he's
more than willing to talk to Lucinda and
their firm um if they need more
information on on how that original work
was done. And then tons of photographs.
Um and I talked to Lucinda today as
well. She spilled milk on her computer
or something and she couldn't access the
drive. So she was having another uh
employee in her firm access the drive
for her. So I think all of that is going
uh very smoothly. Patrick had called
just before the meeting just to ask if
there had been any progress. So I gave
him the same update. Um so um but here
here here are some comments and and
suggestions that I'll leave you with and
kind of her perspective on this whole
thing. So interacting with Lucinda and
maybe you noticed this from some of the
emails that she sent, what what is
becoming really really clear is that the
damage that was done is because of
moisture. And the reason that there's
moisture damage is because we're still
trying to run this thing as a working
fountain with, you know, not the most
robust uh pump situation or predictable
equipment situation and everything. It
seems pretty clear to me, and she's
corroborated this, um, as long as
preserving that fountain means to you
all, to us, that it needs to be in
continuous operation like it was in the
old days. This is going to be a chronic
situation because of the nature of the
terracotta on that old fountain. So, I I
strongly suggest that um preserving this
fountain doesn't necessarily need to or
have to or probably should mean having
it in continuous operation anymore. I
think good preservation is to preserve
the object itself and preserve what's
most value about it from a historical
preservation uh standpoint and that is
those terracotta figures. That's what's
that's what's unique and special about
that fountain, I think. So, um, I
actually would kind of recommend you
abandon
having the lights on and the water
running all the time. Um, you know, goes
without saying when you preserve
something like maybe a historic train or
something, you don't have to have it,
you know, transporting the public around
in order for that to be historic
preservation. You just need to preserve
that the the object so they so that the
people can understand the story. Um, so
I I don't think it's contrary to a
successful conclusion to this
longstanding situation to simply
preserve the fountain, get the damage
done, um, and uh, hopefully it'll never
have to happen again as long as there's
not water in that thing. So, that's
that's kind of my recommendation. Um, I
think they're going to give you a really
good, competitive, very highly
professional bid to get the damage done.
hail. After all this time, it's pretty
clear hail really had nothing to do with
this. Um, it's all damage because when
they scrape pieces off of it, what they
find almost invariably underneath,
particularly close to the base where all
the water is, is mold.
Um, and so those terracotta figures are
just going to continue to be damaged.
Um, I don't think the public has a huge
expectation that in order to have it
preserved, you've got to have it running
like it was in the old days either. So
that's my suggestion
and I will furnish all of the documents
and everything that I have with you. I'm
not disappearing off the face of the
earth and I know I have a lot of stuff
that'll be helpful. So I'll make sure I
keep kind of handing that stuff off to
all of you.
>> I I think that's a really good point. I
mean, I think parks and wreck would
probably love to not have to deal with
an operating fountain, but um yeah, if
depending on how it was constructed
originally, if it wasn't
waterproofed properly, to go and
waterproof it now would be quite a feat.
And I think you're right. I think just
to be able to preserve it so that it
continues to stand there, I mean, if
it's not an operating fountain, then so
be it. I don't know how anyone else
feels.
>> Um, when they were talking about if we
do install a pump, does it have to be
run occasionally or do we just not
install a pump at all? Because I'm
wondering like it would be nice during
frontier days or, you know, when we do
have a bit more traffic in that area or
when um gosh, the terminal is having
those flight programs. I can
>> um you know so is it possible to have it
run occasionally and if so do we have to
have a pump and that pump need to be
used on a semi-regular basis or
something that
>> No, go ahead David. I I can answer that.
>> Patrick said the pump was okay. It was
just the filter was uh
clogging up because it needed like a
secondary filter to take the leaves out
and then this because the the leaves
just need takes a couple leaves to plug
up that filter and then that the pump
then has to work too hard. So I think
it's mainly we could probably run it
every once in a while but we'll have to
come up with some kind of a pre filter
filter or something. Yeah, David, that
was my recollection of all the the kind
of um reconnaissance work that Patrick
Van did on it, too, is that, you know,
the the pump is actually okay. So, I
guess I would recommend that when you're
working, if ultimately Pacific Coast
gives you a bid and you go with it, you
hire them. I just would communicate and
work with them closely and just ask them
that question. You know, how big of a
risk is it going to be to operate it
once in a while? if we get a little bit
of water in there, is it going to mean
we're going to pay a bunch of money to
fix the terracotta again or or not?
Because it would be neat, right? You
could advertise that. It could bring
some awareness to the to the to the
fountain again. But I would just work
with whoever you end up hiring.
Yeah, I I agree that uh it would be a
little disappointing to get through all
of this and then just not be able to run
the fountain at all ever again. Um so I
I agree with Elizabeth. It would be nice
to be able to at least run it. Yeah.
Frontier Days or the aviation festival
or something. But um but yeah, I don't
know. And then I guess I would also just
say that it's it feels good that it
seems like the mountain masonry people
and the Pacific Coast people are both
being very like forthcoming with the
information. Um so that seems like we're
going to at least get correct
information regardless of whether that
means we can't run it as a fountain
after all this.
>> Yeah. I mean at least we're not kind of
ringing our hands and just wondering
anymore. I think we're kind of really
honing in on it and these are these are
good folks who really want you know want
that found to be in good shape. So um
and you have this will bequest the Wanda
estate Gwen Rice estate still sitting
there. Um and uh I I think that kind of
abandoning the idea that it has to run
all the time will be a better
stewardship of those funds too. you're
not going to have to all continuous
money out of that estate to to repair it
over and over again. But, um, I I
certainly hope that when you have your
strategic planning that you get to a
point this year where you can actually
vote to allocate those funds and then
tell the, uh, tell the estate, you know,
that you're completing what you said you
would do with them, including the
interpretation. I know that woman um
with the firm in Commerce City might be
kind of waiting and wondering if uh you
know we're still serious about hiring
her to do the interpretive stuff. So I
think that communication needs to be
picked up again too.
>> Agreed.
>> Um pump house. I don't know if there's
anything new since the last time we
talked that it sounds like they're going
to use it as um
storage area for safe serve and they
might do a little bit of work to restore
it. I don't know Erin if you know any
anything new.
>> Unfortunately, nobody has told me
anything about
>> just a quick question. Um, Gary asked
last time about the barrels
and Charles said that they were going to
do some sampling. Has that been done?
>> Do you know, Aaron?
>> Chair, I have not heard. Um, I can ask
Charles if anything's been done. Um, I
thought that
they were going to ask Councilman
Lebornne because he had had
some things done in the past. But
>> yeah, I think that's true. When he
talked about doing the demolition of the
the two additions on the backside, there
was some pieces done now. Um,
but yeah, I don't think there's any new
information. [laughter]
um watch list items.
I don't know if there's really any
update on any of these. I think that's
something that we'll probably want to
revisit in our strategic plan planning
meeting on what we are doing with those,
if anything. Um if they continue to be
on the watch list item, if we need to
move them up to be something more
important like the tours of schools.
So
has any comments?
New business saving places conference.
So several of us are going. I think
we're all pretty excited. Sounds did
everyone get the information they
needed? I
>> love to see because like I said, I never
got any registration or anything. And
from looking at their website, it looks
like you have to not only register for
the conference, but you have to register
for the individual sessions. And I
haven't registered for anything. So, and
most of them are full already.
>> Has anyone I So, I I downloaded the app
and it kind of pre-registered me to some
of the sessions. I don't know if anyone
else has done anything, but
>> has everyone gotten their confirmation
number and been able to go on there and
um look at
>> Yeah. Basically, you have to log in.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. So,
>> with your confirm, it should be your
email address and your confirmation
number. I I uh registered online,
printed my confirmation number, and um
when you register, it says they'll
they'll email you with further details,
which I haven't received. Um so I have
no confirmation that and I'm registered
to these different sessions. That's
okay. Um regarding the the conference
itself,
uh just as a
Just a general question. What time
should we all be there? Like tomorrow
morning?
>> So registration starts at 9:00 am. Um,
so I I mean you can be there at 9:00
a.m., but they're going to do
registration from 9 to 10 with that
first session starting at 10:00.
>> They give you a name tag and stuff, but
even you're you're pre-registered, but
you need to sign in to get your uh
>> Yeah, they'll give you a name tag.
they'll give you um a a booklet of all
the sessions and and all of that. Um if
you are signing up for any credits,
they'll kind of give you that sheet to
fill out too. So um I would plan on
being there at 9:00
>> and everybody should be registered for
the lunchon that they have as well.
>> Yeah. Which is Thursday. Thursday's the
lunchon.
and everyone everyone knows their
transportation and good.
Okay. Well, I'm excited. I'm excited for
us to come back and talk about it.
>> That sounds exciting.
>> Uh, old business
Louisa Swan building, I guess. Is there
>> So, we talked about this a couple months
ago. I don't know if you remember that
the federal building, Louisa Swain
federal building, which is just right um
to the east of us, they are going to
sell it. Um they want to
put in with the sale. They don't have a
buyer yet, but within with the sale,
they want to put
covenants
um
with
a a monitor, basically a monitor of the
covenants for the facade of the building
and the lobby so that they can protect
the facade in the lobby. Um they want to
name the city as the monitor of of those
covenants. Um, I talked to
um Renee at Chipo and then um also
I think his name is Brad and he's from
um the cultural trust fund in Sheridan.
Um he stated that we really should put a
historic preservation easement on there
instead of covenants. So, he sent me a
historic preservation easement template
um that
we think that the board should work on
um establishing that easement, but that
we would
work on that, but then we need to give
it to the federal government so that
they can put that in the sale of the
property.
>> How much time do we have? Um, I don't
know.
>> Okay.
>> We I I'll I'll check with the contact
that I have um with the federal
government to see when they need this
done by, but and then I'll also send
that template out.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah. What um for somebody who doesn't
know all of the lingo, can you explain
the difference between a covenant and an
easement and why we think an easement is
needed instead of the covenants that we
already sort of discussed and said we
agreed were
seem to be positive for protecting the
historic facade and lobby of the
building. Um, so I don't know for sure,
but I know Renee and the other guy that
I talked to at the cultural trust fund,
they both said that it's going to be um
better enforced through this easement.
Also, um, just working within the city,
we don't recognize covenants at all. Um,
we don't enforce covenants in the city.
So if we saw a building permit come in
for that building and there were
covenants on the building, we we
wouldn't even look at it. We wouldn't we
would just have that building permit
move forward. If there is a recorded
easement on that property, we do have to
enforce that easement.
>> Okay. So do we know like what would be
the next steps on this? like if this is
something we need to do, how do we move
forward to make sure that those are in
place that it protects the historic
elements of the building um before
before they sell it off.
>> We'll have to create that easement
um at least the draft form of that
easement. Um
uh the city attorneys will have to look
at that as well to make sure that it's
all legally agreed upon. um we have to
work with the federal government so that
they can they can take that easement and
put it in with the sale of that
property.
So the first step is to
create that easement that document.
So, the Cultural Trust Fund broke the
mold several years ago and established
the first ever historic preservation
easement funded by the Cultural Trust
Funds long time ago now,
15 years maybe. But Renee Bove, who's
still there, um she she uh had oversight
of that process. So, I think she might
be one of the first people you talk to.
What is this special creature called a
historic preservation easement? Um what
what are the steps that need to take
place? Um, is the cultural trust saying
that they might uh fund it if you if we
applied for a grant to them to do it or
>> um No, they just gave us a template to
use.
>> Okay, so they furnish you the template.
Okay.
>> All right. Well, maybe it's fairly cut
and dry. I don't know. I haven't seen
the template. So,
>> yeah, I think we could probably take a
look at it. Patrick, did you have a
comment?
>> Are you finished, Milward?
I just just use her as a resource. You
know, if you if you're looking at the
template and something's confusing, I
think Renee would be able to give you
good advice.
>> And also the uh other person from
Sheridan because they are the ones that
actually executed the the ones in the
past.
>> Yeah, that's where the first one was was
kind of outside of Ukross.
>> A question that's kind of uh two parts.
One is
does it appear that the I don't know who
sell who would sell it GSA
um is amanable to an easement and second
part
>> who in the city would be responsible for
you know kind of overseeing that
easement was it is it your office Aaron
or you you have to wait for the
attorney's interpretation
>> that's a part of the um within that
easement um you know within the language
of the easement we have to determine who
is going to be responsible for that. So
if it's the board, if it's the planning
office, um
we have to figure that out. I would
assume probably the best way and we
could talk about it is that it would be
received by planning and development but
then it had to be brought forth to our
board to then vote on and approve. But
yeah, I think if we see the template and
maybe that's something we look at at
strategic planning if um you said you
already received it or you're waiting
for the template.
>> I do have the template.
>> So maybe we can look at it then and then
um
>> and I'll call tomorrow my contact at the
GSA to see when they want this done by
and when they plan on putting it up for
sale.
Chair, would it would it be possible to
send the just the draft of the easement
out so that I guess we can start looking
at?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Helpful. So we
>> Thank you.
>> come into the meeting with a little bit
more background. Yeah. [laughter]
>> I guess anything else on that?
Um other business? Um, why don't we
leave Millward's
piece for last and we go to capital
improvement grant.
>> Um, I do have a couple of things just uh
maybe they should have fit under old
business, but um I see that Aeron's been
forwarding some of the previously
submitted annual reports to the CLG. So,
that'll give you something to go on.
>> Okay.
>> Um the the actual preparation has been
really led by staff in the past. I see
Lonnie Olsen's signature on a bunch of
these. Um, but the fortunately a lot of
it is just yes. It's a it's a form and
you just answer yes no questions for a
lot of it. And then I think there's got
to be some documentation of the work
that you did this last year. So again, I
think the right move here is to get a
hold of Katie um and ask if there's a
possibility for an extension on
submitting the report. Um, I think
they'll they'll be pretty pretty good to
work with.
Okay.
Well, do we want to talk about capital
improvement grant first and then we'll
um leave the last bit of business for
you?
Um, so I guess the capital improvement
grant for Atlas Theater. Um, yeah,
>> sure. Um, just to give an update that
the Atlas Theater has requested a
capital improvement grant through the
DDA um to repair their windows um that
got hail damaged in that storm in
August. And so that's just going through
their department right now.
um they are just replacing like for like
um but we just wanted you to be aware of
it. Um one of the things so I I've been
sitting in on the DDA uh board meetings.
Um, unfortunately
the our board has not been heavily
involved yet as far as some of those
capital improvement and uh facade
grants, but I have uh spoken with Sophia
um and I'm going to attend their work
session in a couple of weeks and then
I've invited them to come to our work
session so that we can find a way of
integrating um because I do think when
we're talking about capital improvement
grants and facade improvement grants
that when we're talking about our
historic downtown that we should
probably have some say in that. Um and
one of those one of the things that we
discussed was um coming up with those
design guidelines um of what we need to
follow for downtown. So that I mean
that's a topic I'd like to bring up for
strategic planning, but I I do think
that we need to have a little bit more
integrated relationship with DDA moving
forward. So
Yeah, and we've been talking about the
design guidelines for several years. So,
I think it would definitely be it might
be something that would be good to sort
of move up the list in terms of what's
priority for us to do. Um, especially
because then it would give us the
ability to chime in on this type of need
more. Um, I think it's great that the
Atlas is applying for um
the grant to to repair the windows, but
um yeah, it it would also be nice if we
were in a position where we could make
sure they're saying, "Yeah, you're
replacing like for like, but can we make
sure that any money that is being um
given for that type of thing is also
like following the um
um Department of Interior standards for
historic preservation and that
Absolutely.
Yes. Anything else on Atlas?
All right, Millward.
>> Yes, Madam Chair. is your last meeting
and I I mean I'm upset that you are
leaving but I I understand and I mean
personally for when I came onto this
board I learned a lot from you and have
definitely en enjoyed working with you
and hopefully we continue to collaborate
even if you aren't an official member.
Um but I guess did I mean do you have
any last last comments?
>> Never ask a Simpson in Wyoming if they
have last comments because we'll be here
forever. No. Well, I always enjoy
listening to you, so
>> yeah. No, I do. I do have a few. Um,
so it's been a real honor and privilege
and pleasure to work with all of you. I
I think that um what you do is
extraordinarily important. Um, and so I
hope you carry that understanding of of
uh of what you do for this community and
the stewardship you have of this
community's historic identity is crucial
part of who we are in this magic city on
the plains where we promote and sell our
history and and benefit from it
economically and pride ourselves in it.
Well, you are the organization in town
that has the most important role in uh
in continuing to honor our history. um
really happy with successes like um just
most recently I think we had a lot to do
with um taking the pump house off the
chopping block and so that's really
wonderful. Um keep I would just urge you
to keep in mind a couple of things that
are are really unique opportunities that
you have that most CLGs don't have. Um,
for one, you guys have money thanks to
um to to to this just wild man that we
all love so much who makes ornaments and
gives you tens of thousands of dollars.
So, use it. Use it. It's just sitting in
the bank. Find projects you want to
accomplish and use it. Um, there are so
many CLGs that just are languishing
without any money. Most of what they do
is ceremonial, but you've got the
ability to actually deploy some
resources and and do it. So, I I hope
during your strategic plan that you'd
understand that what you're doing can be
fueled by that money that's um that's
sitting there. Um couple of just silly
housekeeping things. Another part of
your potential responsibility. I never
really had the time to attend to it, but
as a CLG, you're in a position to
comment on section 106 uh undertakings
and I get requests to do that like cell
phone towers. You know, this CLG,
they're compelled by the shipo 106
process to ask give you an opportunity
to comment and there might be some that
are a significant enough impact to a
historical resource that you want to
comment on it. So, um, uh, if I keep
getting those, I'll forward them to you,
but I guess and Erin, those all come
across the transom to you as well, don't
they? Yeah. So, if you can make sure
those come to to Amber's attention. Um,
I hope you give another shot at the um
at the uh um ordinance that we uh almost
got over the finish line with demolition
by neglect. I mean, you heard your own
city council leaison say you should try
it again. Um, if you do that, I'd be
happy as a citizen to help you in any
any way that I can. I'm not going
anywhere. I'm going to continue to
advocate for you and for all things
historic preservation here in uh in
Cheyenne. Um, you can't do anything
successfully without the planning
office's support. And I think one of the
things that I'm really pleased with in
my 10 years that that support has been
there for the most part. I think that it
slipped a little bit recently. Um I I so
I guess given that you only meet once a
month um when Charles or anybody in the
staff says we'll look into that or we
will get back to you on that. I think
there needs to be some pretty robust
oversight of that. Like there were
plenty of things that we established
last month that Charles could have put
in a written report to you instead of
just not being here and having no report
because as we've all been frustrated on
occasion in the past with like getting
the getting your contracts going. Well,
you're all volunteers, you know, and you
lose a lot of time if there's been a
promise that there will be an update and
there's no update then you've lost 30
days just right there. So, I don't know
if uh way maybe one mechanism I'd
recommend is when there's an agreement
to get back to you with information, put
a put a deadline on it that you both
agree on. Could we please get an email
from you about this by such and such a
time? And Elizabeth, I mean, this is
this is your personal situation with uh
not being compensated. I'm sure your
contract says something about how you're
supposed to be compensated. So, if
you're not getting satisfaction, go to
go to a higher level about it. I mean,
to me, that's not acceptable. Um, both
the delay in getting those done,
regardless of how busy things are, and
not in you not getting paid. Um, don't
just be satisfied with that and you can
be respectful and everything can go
forward with great positivity. I think
you've got a planning director who
understands historic preservation and
truly loves it and wants to support it,
who's under a lot of uh time constraints
and pressure and and things, but uh no
one's going to advocate for you in terms
of getting work done but yourselves. So,
there's some suggestions for you going
forward.
>> Um
I've loved every minute of it. Really
enjoy working with all of you and I'm
going to miss it. and uh maybe I'll be
here as an audience member to bug you
sometimes. If there's anything that
comes to the city council um that
requires some public advocacy, you can
count on my support there, too.
So, just thank you. Thanks. Thanks for
all your work and uh all of the fun
times we've had and all of the extra
time you put in to show up to do things.
I know how busy everybody is. I hope
you've valued it and got as much out of
it as I have.
So, good luck going forward. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> We have a plaque coming for you. Um
when it when it gets delivered, we'll
get it to you. [laughter]
>> Did we run out of bricks? [laughter] We
used to get bricks.
>> Yeah.
>> Yep. We still have a brick.
Does anyone else want to say anything
before we adjourn?
>> I just wanted to say thank you to Miller
again for all of your leadership. Very
appreciated.
>> You're very welcome. Thank Thank you.
>> Yes, you you've left really big shoes to
fill. So,
>> you guys are going to be great.
I'm really excited for all the
inspiration you're going to get from
your uh time down in Colorado. I didn't
realize it's tomorrow, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Great.
>> Well, I I actually was really confused
because when I first saw um the
schedule, it said 7 a.m. today and
that's why that's when I thought it
started and then I realized it was just
some ceremonial thing and thanks. Yeah,
obviously did not go. So, but no, I'm
excited. But, okay. Well, I guess we can
adjourn.
>> Aren't you going to bang the gavvel like
really loud?